Pease, Arthur Stanley, 1881-1964. Arthur Stanley Pease correspondence and compositions, 1870-1963 (MS Am 1804): Guide.
Arthur Stanley Pease correspondence and compositions,
- I. Letters to Arthur Stanley Pease
  - Hopkins, Milton. 1 letter; [n.d.], (387)
  - Horn, Robert Chisolm. 1 letter; 1945., (388)
  - Horton, Douglas, 1891- 3 letters; 1955-1963., (389)
  - Horton, Mildred McAfee. 3 letters; 1959-1962., (390)
  - Hough, Lynn Harold, 1877- 1 letter; 1957., (391)
  - Houghton, Herbert Pierrepont, 1880- 3 letters; 1937-1941., (392)
  - Houghton, Walter Edwards, 1904- 1 letter; 1957. With notes by Arthur Stanley Pease., (393)
  - Hovey, Mary Trowbridge. 3 letters; 1936-1938., (394)
  - Howard, William Guild. 5 letters; 1935-1951., (395)
  - Howe, Lois Lilley. 1 letter; 1945., (396)
  - Howe, Mark Anthony De Wolfe, 1864-1960. 5 letters; 1908-1935., (397)
  - Howe, Mark De Wolfe, 1906-1967. 1 letter; 1948., (398)
  - Howland, Adelaide Stackpole. 1 letter; 1956., (399)
  - Hrdlicka, Clement L. 1 letter; 1932., (400)
  - Hubbell, Harry Mortimer, 1881- 3 letters; 1949 and [n.d.], (401)
  - Hull, G. Harvey. 2 letters; 1950-1960., (402)
  - Hull, Vernam Edward, 1895- 1 letter; 1952., (403)
  - Hulley, Karl Kelchner. 37 letters; 1936-1962 and [n.d.], (404)
  - Hunt, C.S. 1 letter; 1914., (405)
  - Hutchins, Robert Maynard, 1899- 2 letters; 1930-1943., (406)
  - Hutchinson, Mark E. 1 letter; 1945., (407)
  - Hutton, Maurice, 1856- 3 letters; [n.d.], (408)
  - Immerwahr, Henry R. 2 letters; 1946., (409)
  - Jackson, Arthur M. 2 letters; 1946 and [n.d.], (410)
  - Jackson, Carl Newell. 81 letters; 1911-[1946], (411)
  - Jackson, Dugald Caleb, 1865- 1 letter; 1938., (412)
  - Jackson, Kenneth, 1909- 2 letters; 1942., (413)
  - Jackson, William A. 2 letters; 1946-1947., (414)
  - Jackson, William Alexander, 1905-1964. 4 letters; 1948-1962., (415)
  - Jacobs, Thornwell, 1877- 1 letter; 1932., (416)
  - Jaeger, Ruth. 2 letters; 1958-1961., (417)
  - Jaeger, Wernes Wilhelm, 1888-1961. 21 letters; 1939-1958 and [n.d.], (418)
  - James, Arthur Curtiss. 1 letter; 1931., (419)
  - James, Edmond Janes, 1855-1925. 7 letters; 1910-1917. Nos.1 and 2 signed by secretary., (420)
  - James, William, 1882-1961. 6 letters; 1934-1959., (421)
  - Jarcho, Saul. 1 letter; 1955., (422)
  - Jenks, Paul Rockwell, 1872- 2 letters; 1922-1936., (423)
  - Jessup, R.F. 1 letter; 1930., (424)
  - Jewett, James Richard, 1862-1943. 2 letters; 1941-1942., (425)
  - Joensson, Nina. 1 letter; 1963., (426)
  - Johnson, Allan Chester, 1881- 6 letters; 1941-1946., (427)
  - Johnson, Alvin, 1874- 1 letter; 1941., (428)
  - Johnson, Arthur C. 1 letter; 1936., (429)
  - Johnson, Dudley. 1 letter; 1953., (430)
  - Johnson, Franklin Plotinus, 1896- 2 letters; 1937-1938., (431)
  - Johnson, Sherman Elbridge, 1908- 7 letters; 1945-1949., (432)
  - Jones, Harrie Stuart Vedder. 8 letters; 1920-1941., (433)
  - Jones, Leslie Webber, 1900- 1 letter; 1937., (434)
  - Jones, Robert Epes. 2 letters; 1947., (435)
  - Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931. 2 letters; 1913-1927. No.1 sigged by secretary., (436)
  - Jordan, J.K. 1 letter; 1950., (437)
  - Jordan, Wilbur Kitchener, 1902- 10 letters; 1944-1953., (438)
  - Judson, Mabel H. 2 letters; 1959 and [n.d.], (439)
  - Karo, Georg Heinrich, 1872- 1 letter; 1906., (440)
  - Kates, Frederick Ward, 1910- 1 letter; 1943., (441)
  - Kaye, Frederick Benjamin, 1892- 1 letter; 1923., (442)
  - Kelsey, Francis Willey, 1858-1927. 1 letter; 1923., (443)
  - Kennedy, Mona Hadnett. 2 letter; 1951., (444)
  - Kennedy, Sargent. 1 letter; 1945., (445)
  - Kent, Roland Grubb, 1877-1952. 14 letters; 1938-1950., (446)
  - Keyes, Clinton Walker, 1888- 1 letter; 1941., (447)
  - Killian, Laurence B. 2 letters; 1941-1953., (448)
  - King, Samuel. 1 letter; 1941., (449)
  - King, Samuel Bowles. 1 letter; 1907., (450)
  - King, Stanley, 1883- 24 letters; 1927-1950 and [n.d.], (451)
  - Kinley, David, 1861- 3 letters; 1911-1938., (452)
  - Kinsolving, Arthur Lee. 5 letters; 1930-1932 and [n.d.], (453)
  - Kittredge, George Lyman, 1860-1941. 8 letters; 1923-[1939] and [n.d.], (454)
  - Kline, W.A. 2 letters; 1935- 1940., (455)
  - Knapp, Charles, 1868- 3 letters; 1921., (456)
  - Knapp, Fred A. 1 letter; 1938., (457)
  - Knight, William Francis Jackson, 1895-1964. 5 letters; 1930-1944., (458)
  - Kobayawa, Count A. 2 letters; 1927 and [n.d.], (459)
  - Kraemer, Casper John, 1895- 8 letters; 1928-1942. No.8 with a copy; concerns the American Philological Association., (460)
  - Kroll, Wilhelm, 1869-1939. 4 letters; 1922-1937., (461)
  - Ladd, George Eldon, 1911- 1 letter; 1949., (462)
  - Laing, Gordon Jennings, 1869-1945. 1 letter; 1921., (463)
  - Laird, Arthur Gordon. 4 letters; 1925-1927., (464)
  - Lamb, Arthur Becket, 1880-1952. 1 letter; 1942., (465)
  - Lamprecht, Sterling Power, 1890- 1 letter; 1937., (466)
  - Landon, Hugh McK. 1 letter; 1942., (467)
  - Lane, George R. 3 letters; 1950., (468)
  - Lane, K. 1 letter; 1921., (469)
  - Langenheim, Jean. 1 letter; [1962], (470)
  - Lanman, Charles Rockwell, 1850-1941. 10 letters; 1908-1937., (471)
  - La Piana, George, 1879- 8 letters; [1936]-1953., (472)
  - Larsen, Jakob Aall Ottesen. 8 letters; 1939-1959., (473)
  - Larson, Laurence Marcellus, 1868-1938. 1 letter; 1920., (474)
  - Lattimore, Richmond Alexander, 1906- 4 letters; 1940-1946., (475)
  - Laughton, Eric, 1911- 1 letter; 1950., (476)
  - Lawless, Mary E. 4 letters; 1946-1947., (477)
  - Lee, Roger Irving, 1881- 4 letters; 1959-[1962] and [n.d.], (478)
  - Lee, Sylvia. 2 letters; 1945., (479)
  - Leetch, Florence K. 1 letter; 1937. See also Perley Oakland Place to Florence K. Leetch, no.(1115)., (480)
  - Leighton, L.B. 1 letter; 1938., (481)
  - Lenz, Friedrich Walther, 1896- 25 letters; 1921-1952., (482)
  - Leon, Harry Joshua. 1 letter; 1959., (483)
  - Lessells, Gladys. 1 letter; [1961], (484)
  - Levine, Philip, 1922- 14 letters; 1949-1961., (485)
  - Levy, Harry Louis, 1906- 6 letters; 1945-1951., (486)
  - Lewis, Frederick Thomas, 1875-1951. 8 letters; 1938-1945., (487)
  - Lewis, William Mather, 1878- 1 letter; 1931., (488)
  - Liljegren, Sten Bodvar, 1885- 1 letter; 1925., (489)
  - Lind, Levi Robert, 1906- 2 letters; 1951., (490)
  - Linforth, Ivan Mortimer, 1879- 8 letters; 1941-1954., (491)
  - Lippincott, James Janney. 1 letter; 1930., (492)
  - Lipscomb, Herbert Cannon, 1882- 6 letters; 1954 and [n.d.], (493)
  - Litchfield, Henry Wheatland. 1 letter; 1919., (494)
  - Little, Alan McNaughton Gordon. 7 letters; 1940-1942 and [n.d.], (495)
  - Livingstone, Sir Richard Winn, 1880-1957. 3 letters; 1941., (496)
  - Lockwood, Dean Putnam, 1883- 4 letters; 1935-1939 and [n.d.], (497)
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1902- 7 letters; 1937-1952. No.6, see also Jack K. McFall to Henry Cabot Lodge, no.(1089), (498)
  - Löve, Doris. 2 letters; 1960-1961., (499)
  - Lofstedt, Einar. 1 letter; 1935., (500)
  - Long, Bayard. 1 letter; 1960., (501)
  - Lord, Albert Bates. 1 letter; 1936., (502)
  - Lord, Louis Eleazer, 1875-1957. 2 letters; 1944-1953., (503)
  - Lovett, Robert Woodberry. 1 letter; 1953., (504)
  - Lowe, Clarence George, 1897- 3 letters; 1928-1931., (505)
  - Lowell, Abbott Lawrence, 1856-1943. 5 letters; 1931-1933., (506)
  - Lowell, Ralph. 3 letters; 1948-[1949], (507)
  - Lowes, J.W. 1 letter; 1936., (508)
  - Luce, Robert, 1862-1946. 2 letters; 1934-1939., (509)
  - Luck, Georg, 1926- 1 letter; 1957., (510)
  - Lund, Fred Bates, 1869-1950. 1 letter; 1941., (511)
  - Lynch, Charles Arthur. 1 letter; 1944., (512)
  - Lynn, Caro, 1894- 3 letters; 1934-1939., (513)
  - McCartney, Eugene Stock, 1883- 17 letters; 1921-1949., (514)
  - McClure, James Gore King, 1848-1932. 1 letter; 1928., (515)
  - McClure, Matthew Thompson, 1883- 2 letters; 1947., (516)
  - McConaughy, James Lukens, 1887- 1 letter; 1931., (517)
  - McCord, David, 1897- 76 letters; 1944-1962 and [n.d.], (518)
  - McCracken, George Englert, 1904- 2 letters; [1948]-1951., (519)
  - McDaniel, Walton Brooks, 1871- 15 letters; 1943-1958., (520)
  - McDermott, William Coffman, 1907- 7 letters; 1939-1950., (521)
  - Macdonald, Janet Malcolm, 1891- 2 letters; 1917-1936., (522)
  - Mackail, John William, 1859-1945. 1 letter; 1935., (523)
  - Mackay, Roberta M.D. 1 letter; 1962., (524)
  - MacKendrick, Paul Lachlan, 1914- 7 letters; 1937-1946., (525)
  - McKenzie, Kenneth, 1870- 1 letter; 1927., (526)
  - McKeon, Newton Felch, 1904- 3 letters; 1944-1959., (527)
  - McKinlay, Arthur Patch, 1871- 7 letters; 1943-[1953] and [n.d.], (528)
  - Macnair, Louise, 2 letters; 1959-1960., (529)
  - McNamee, Barbara. 3 letters; 1959-1961., (530)
  - Macomber, Herrick Mower. 1 letter; 1937., (531)
  - McVey, Frank Le Rond, 1869- 1 letter, 1931. Mimeographed., (532)
  - Magie, David, 1877- 1 letter; 1952., (533)
  - Magoffin, Ralph Van Deman, 1874- 1 letter; 1927., (534)
  - Magoun, Francis Peabody, 1895- 1 letter; 1941., (535)
  - Maker, Veda M. 1 letter; 1962., (536)
  - Malone, Dumas, 1892- 1 letter; 1938., (537)
  - Malye, Jean. 3 letters; 1946-1950., (538)
  - Mandra, Raymond, 1895- 3 letters; 1938-1940., (539)
  - Manitius, Maximilian, 1858-1933. 1 letter; 1923., (540)
  - Marcus, Ralph, 1900- 2 letters; 1943., (541)
  - Marique, Joseph Marie Felix. 2 letters; 1942. With bulletins 1,2,5 and 6 of the Fordham University Project, Prosographia Christiana., (542)
  - Marsupan, J. 1 letter; 1950., (543)
  - Marsh, Daniel Lash, 1880- 3 letters; 1930-1940., (544)
  - Marucchi, Orazio, 1852-1931. 1 letter; 1913., (545)
  - Mason, Cora Catherine. 2 letters; 1948 and [n.d.], (546)
  - Matthews, Brander, 1852-1929. 2 letters; 1913-1915., (547)
  - Matthiessen, Francis Otto, 1902-1950. 1 letter; 1937., (548)
  - Matthison, Edith Wynner. 3 letters; 1932., (549)
  - Means, James Howard, 1885- 1 letter; 1943., (550)
  - Mendell, Clarence Whittlesey, 1883- 1 letter; 1954., (551)
  - Meritt, Benjamin Dean, 1899- 7 letters; 1940-1953. No.1 mimeographed, No.4 signed by secretary., (552)
  - Merrill, Elmer Truesdell, 1860-1936. 2 letters; 1920-1923., (553)
  - Merrill, Imogene W. 1 letter; [n.d.], (554)
  - Merriman, Albert. 3 letters; 1942-1943., (555)
  - Merrow, Chester Earl, 1906- 1 letter; 1954., (556)
  - Messing, Gordon Myron. 1 letter; [1942], (557)
  - Meyer, Edward, 1855-1930. 2 letters; 1910., (558)
  - Michell, Humfrey, 1883- 20 letters; 1943-1954., (559)
  - Mierow, Charles Christopher, 1883- 2 letters; 1927-1946., (560)
  - Miller, Frank Justus, 1858- 1 letter; [1908], (561)
  - Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1868-1953. 1 letter; 1932., (562)
  - Millward, Arthur. 2 letters;1951., (563)
  - Mitchell, Benjamin Wiestling, 1861- 2 letters; 1935-1937., (564)
  - Monroe, John H. 1 letter; 1938., (565)
  - Moody, Paul Dwight, 1879- 1 letter; 1927., (566)
  - Moore, Albert Hanford. 2 letters; 1924-1933., (567)
  - Moore, Clifford Herschel, 1866-1931. 9 letters; 1919-1927., (568)
  - Moore, Edward C. 3 letters; 1927-1931., (569)
  - Moore, Frank Gardner, 1865- 17 letters; 1908-1954., (570)
  - Moore, George Foot, 1851-1931. 16 letters; 1911-1929 and [n.d.], (571)
  - Moore, John. 1 letter; 1945., (572)
  - Moore, Mary S. (Hanford), d.1924. 2 letters; [n.d.], (573)
  - Moorehead, Warren King, 1866- 1 letter; 1916., (574)
  - Moors, Arthur W. 2 letters; 1946., (575)
  - Morgan, Morris Hicky, 1859-1910. 3 letters; 1903-1909., (576)
  - Morin, Germain, 1861-1946. 4 letters; 1908-1912., (577)
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1887- 5 letters; 1933-1935 and [n.d.], (578)
  - Morize, André, 1883- 1 letter; 1936., (579)
  - Morley, Herbert S. 1 letter; 1927., (580)
  - Morrow, Dwight Whitney, 1873-1931. 6 letters; 1927-1930., (581)
  - Morrow, Elizabeth. 1 letter; 1931., (582)
  - Morrow, Jay Johnson, 1870. 1 letter; [1931], (583)
  - Moser, Arthur H. 2 letters; 1938., (584)
  - Moss, Charles Melville, 1853- 48 letters; 1912-1926 and [n.d.] No.43 with a letter from Frances Moss to Arthur Stanley Pease., (585)
  - Moss, Frances E. 2 letters; 1926., (586)
  - Mouterde, René. 1 letter; 1927., (587)
  - Münscher, Karl, 1871- 2 letters; 1923 and [n.d.], (588)
  - Mulhern, George I., Jr. 1 letter; 1950., (589)
  - Munn, James Buell. 147 letters; 1933-1956., (590)
  - Munn, Ruth. 2 letters; 1959-1960., (591)
  - Murdock, Kenneth Ballard, 1895- 4 letters; 1932-1935 and [n.d.], (592)
  - Murley, Joseph Clyde. 1 letter; 1940., (593)
  - Murphy, Charles Theophilus. 2 letters; 1940-1947., (594)
  - Murphy, Paul Robert. 3 letters; 1946-1947., (595)
  - [Mussey, Henry Raymond, 1875-1940] 1 letter; 1909. Copy., (596)
  - Myerson, Abraham, 1881-1948. 2 letters; 1942., (597)
  - Mylonas, George Emmanuel, 1898- 1 letter; 1949., (598)
  - Mynors, Roger Aubrey Baskerville. 1 letter; 1947., (599)
  - Nash, Norman Burdett, 1888- 1 letter; 1946., (600)
  - Neilson, William Allen, 1869-1946. 2 letters; 1928-1931. No.2 addressed to Esther Stocks, secretary to Arthur Stanley Pease., (601)
  - New Hampshire Dept. of Public Works and Highways. 1 letter; 1962., (602)
  - Nichols, Harry Peirce, 1850-1940. 2 letters; 1929-[1930]., (603)
  - Nock, Arthur Darby, 1902-1963. 58 letters; 1932-1959 and [n.d.], (604)
  - Norden, Edward, 1868-1941. 9 letters; 1935-1939 and [n.d.], (605)
  - Norden, Irmgard. 3 letters; 1937-1941., (606)
  - Norden, Marie. 2 letters; 1936-1941., (607)
  - Norton, Grace. 2 letters; [n.d.], (608)
  - Notopoulas, James Anastasios. 12 letters; 1932-1954., (609)
  - Nye, Irene. 1 letter; 1940., (610)
  - O'Brien, Helen V. 1 letter; 1953., (611)
  - Oertel, Hanns, 1868- 1 letter; 1903., (612)
  - Ogilly, R.B. 8 letters; 1928-1936., (613)
  - Ogle, Marbury Bladen, 1879- 4 letters; 1930-1940., (614)
  - Oldfather, Agnes G. 1 letter; 1929, (615)
  - Oldfather, William Abbott, 1880-1945. 132 letters; 1913-1944., (616)
  - Olds, George Daniel, 1853-1931. 18 letters; 1924-1931., (617)
  - Oliver, Revilo Pendleton, 1910- 7 letters; 1946-1954., (618)
  - Olsen, Erling C. 3 letters; 1935-1937., (619)
  - Osborn, Albert Sherman, 1858-1946. 2 letters; 1940., (620)
  - Otis, Brooks. 33 letters; [1920]-[1961] and [n.d.], (621)
  - Otis, Christine. 1 letter; [n.d.], (622)
  - Otis, W.F. 2 letters; 1961 and [n.d.], (623)
  - Overmeyer, Kathleen. 1 letter; 1935., (624)
  - Page, Curtis Hidden, 1870-1946. 1 letter; 1938., (625)
  - Page, Frederick Harlan. 9 letters; 1932-1944. Nos.3 and 7-9 signed by secretary. No.1 with a note by Ellen Stacey., (626)
  - [Page, J.M.] 1 letter; 1924., (627)
  - Page, Thomas Ethelbert. 2 letters; 1935., (628)
  - Palmer, Ernest Jesse. 1 letter; 1960., (629)
  - Paradise, Scott Hurtt, 1891- 2 letters; 1957., (630)
  - Park, Charles Edwards, 1873- 1 letter; 1942., (631)
  - Park, John Edgar, 1879- 4 letters; 1928-1941., (632)
  - Parker, George Howard, 1864- 1 letter; 1945., (633)
  - Parkman, Francis. 4 letters; 1934-1936 and [n.d.], (634)
  - Parry, Milman, d.1935. 1 letter; 1935., (635)
  - Parsons, Edward S. 1 letter; 1927. Addressed to Ruth C. Butterworth, secretary to Arthur Stanley Pease., (636)
  - Partridge, Frank Charles, 1861- 1 letter; 1930., (637)
  - Paton, James Morton, 1863-1944. 7 letters; 1906-1941 and [n.d.], (638)
  - Paton, Lucy Allen. 2 letters; 1940 and [n.d.] No.2 lacks beginning., (639)
  - Pauli, Adolph. 20 letters; 1916-1938. Nos. 17 and 18 signed by secretary., (640)
  - Peabody, Francis Greenwood, 1847-1936. 3 letters; [1934-1935] and [n.d.], (641)
  - Peabody, James Bishop, 1922- 2 letters; 1947-[1950], (642)
  - Peachy, Frederic. 1 letter; 1948., (643)
  - Pearson, Roy Messer, 1914- 3 letters; 1957-1958., (644)
  - Pease, Abby Frances (Cutter) 3 letters; 1909-1924., (645)
  - Pease, Samuel James. 1 letter; 1942., (646)
  - Peebles, Bernard Mann. 11 letters; 1937-[1962], (647)
  - Pence, Mary Elizabeth. 1 letter; 1941., (648)
  - Perry, Ben Edwin, 1892- 14 letters; 1945-1954 and [n.d.], (649)
  - Perry, Bliss, 1860-1954. 5 letters; 1937-1951., (650)
  - Perry, Lewis. 2 letters; 1941 and [n.d.] No.2 signed by secretary., (651)
  - Perry, Ralph Barton, 1876-1957. 1 letter; 1941., (652)
  - Peterkin, L. Denis. 3 letters; 1930-1941., (653)
  - Petersson, Torsten, 1878- 2 letters; 1908-1923., (654)
  - Petrie, George. 1 letter; 1927., (655)
  - Pfeiffer, Robert Henry, 1892-1958. 2 letters; 1950-1953., (656)
  - Phalen, George Stone. 1 letter; 1942., (657)
  - Pharr, Clyde, 1883- 2 letters; 1933-1942., (658)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943. 2 letters; 1931., (659)
  - Philippson, Ernst Alfred, 1900- 4 letters; 1941-1947., (660)
  - Philippson, Robert Israel. 2 letters; 1940-1941., (661)
  - Phillips, Henry, 1903- 13 letters; 1926-1959 and [n.d.], (662)
  - Phillips, J.L. 1 letter; 1938., (663)
  - Pitman, Paul M. 1 letter; 1950., (664)
  - Plasberg, Otto, 1869-1924. 2 letters; 1920-1921., (665)
  - Platner, James Winthrop, 1865-1921. 2 letters; 1908-1915., (666)
  - Platt, Peggy. 1 letter; [n.d.], (667)
  - Plimpton, Calvin Hastings, 1918- 1 letter; 1963., (668)
  - Plumpe, Joseph Conrad, 1901- 2 letters; 1940-1947., (669)
  - Pohlenz, Max, 1872-1962. 8 letters; 1921-1949., (670)
  - Poole, James Plummer. 2 letters; 1961., (671)
  - Porter, Martha Harmon. 1 letter; 1945. Concerning Austin M. Harmon., (672)
  - Post, Chandler Rathfon, 1881- 1 letter; 1945., (673)
  - Post, Levi Arnold, 1889- 18 letters; 1936-1959 and [n.d.] No.3 with a copy of a letter from L.A. Post to G.L. Hendrickson. Concerning the American Philological Association., (674)
  - Postgate, John Percival, 1853-1926. 1 letter; 1923., (675)
  - Pound, Roscoe, 1870-1964. 1 letter; 1936., (676)
  - Poynter, Horace Marting 3 letters; 1938, (677)
  - Pratt, James Bissett, 1875-1944. 1 letter; 1941., (678)
  - Prescott, Henry Washington, 1874- 8 letters; 1935-1937., (679)
  - Prindle, Lester M. 1 letter; 1945., (680)
  - Pugsley, James W. 3 letters; 1935-1937., (681)
  - Pulgram, Ernst. 1 letter; 1956. Mimeographed., (682)
  - Pusey, Nathan Marsh, 1907- 1 letter; 1958., (683)
  - Putnam, Harrington, 1851- 1 letter; 1927., (684)
  - Putnam, Herbert, 1861-1955. 1 letter; 1931., (685)
  - Putnam, Michael Courtenay Jenkins. 1 letter; 1956., (686)
  - Radford, Robert Somerville, 1869- 5 letters; 1924-1932. No.4 see also R.S.Radford to Roy C. Flickinger, no.(1121), (687)
  - Radin, Max, 1880-1950. 1 letter; 1934., (688)
  - Rainey, Henry Thomas, 1860-1934. 1 letter; 1931., (689)
  - Rand, Belle P. 2 letters; [1945]-1946., (690)
  - Rand, Edward Kennard, 1871-1945. 88 letters; 1914-1945 and [n.d.] No.29, see also EK. Rand to Harvard University Press, no.(1123) and to Mason Hammond, no.(1122) No.34 and 48 with notes by Arthur Stanley Pease. See also no.(335), (691)
  - Randolph, Charles Brewster. 9 letters; [1904?-1929] and [n.d.] No.3 with a note by Arthur Stanley Pease., (692)
  - Rathbone, Perry Townsend, 1911- 1 letter; [n.d.], (693)
  - Rathbun, Lawrance W. 1 letter; 1955., (694)
  - Raynor, T.G. 1 letter; 1921., (695)
  - Reed, Chester T. 1 telegram; 1933., (696)
  - Reiche, Harald Anton Thrap. 1 letter; 1945., (697)
  - Reid, James Smith, 1846-1926. 2 letters; 1921., (698)
  - Reiter, Siegfried. 30 letters; 1908-1938., (699)
  - Rensi, Giuseppe, 1871- 1 letter; 1921., (700)
  - Rentoul, Anthony. 1 letter; 1962., (701)
  - Rexine, John Efstratios. 4 letters; 1952-1954., (702)
  - Rhees, Rush, 1860-1939. 1 letter; 1930., (703)
  - Rice, Alexander Hamilton, 1875- 1 letter; 1942., (704)
  - Rice, Warner Grenelle. 6 letters; 1922-[1941] and [n.d.], (705)
  - Richards, George Chatterton, 1867-1951. 1 letter; 1935., (706)
  - Richards, John Francis Chatterton. 12 letters; 1947-1952 and [n.d.], (707)
  - Richardson, Theresa W. 1 letter; 1938., (708)
  - Richardson, William King. 1 letter; 1941., (709)
  - Riddehough, Geoffrey Blundell. 3 letters; 1950-1962., (710)
  - Riess, Ernst. 2 letters; 1921-1923., (711)
  - Riley, Lila Stevenson. 2 letters; 1947., (712)
  - Ripley, Alfred Laurence, 1858- 1 letter; 1928., (713)
  - Robbins, Frank Egleston, 1884- 4 letters; 1939 and [n.d.], (714)
  - Robinson, Charles Alexander, 1900- 3 letters; 1938., (715)
  - Robinson, David Moore, 1880-1958. 7 letters; 1926-1955 and [n.d.], (716)
  - Robinson, Edward A. 36 letters; 1938-1958., (717)
  - Robinson, Fred Norris, 1871-1966. 6 letters; 1917-[1942], (718)
  - Robinson, George N. 1 letter; 1942., (719)
  - Robinson, Rachel Louisa (Sargent) 1891- 8 letters; 1950-1952 and [n.d.], (720)
  - Robinson, Rodney Potter, 1890- 4 letters; 1919-1927., (721)
  - Rockwell, William Walker, 1874- 2 letters; 1907-1908., (722)
  - Roebuck, Carl Angus, 1914- 1 letter; 1955., (723)
  - Roelofs, Howard Dykema. 2 letters; 1935-1944., (724)
  - Rogers, Lindsay, 1891- 1 letter; 1927., (725)
  - Rogers, Robert Samuel, 1900- 2 letters; 1951., (726)
  - Rolfe, John Carew, 1859-1943. 4 letters; 1921-1933., (727)
  - Rollins, Hyder Edward, 1889-1958. 1 letter; 1934., (728)
  - Rollins, Reed Clark, 1911- 1 letter; 1952., (729)
  - Ropes, Alice L. 1 letter; [1936], (730)
  - Ropes, James Hardy, 1866-1933. 4 letters; 1922-1932., (731)
  - Rose, Herbert Jennings, 1883- 2 letters; 1935-1941., (732)
  - Rosenmeyer, Thomas Gustav. 5 letters; [n.d.], (733)
  - Roundy, Rodney W. 1 letter; 1932., (734)
  - Rouse, William Henry Denham, 1863-1950. 3 letters; 1936-1941., (735)
  - Rowe, Leo Stanton, 1871- 1 letter; 1927., (736)
  - Rowell, Henry Thompson, 1904- 1 letter; 1946., (737)
  - Rowland, George M. 1 telegram; 1929., (738)
  - Rowland, William Tingle, 1881- 3 letters; 1927-1928., (739)
  - Ruch, Michel. 1 letter; 1948., (740)
  - Ruckmick, Christian Alban, 1886- 1 letter; 1930., (741)
  - Rugg, Arthur Prentice, 1862-1938. 6 letters; 1927-1931., (742)
  - Rugg, Charles B. 1 letter; 1930., (743)
  - Russell, Richard Manning, 1891- 2 letters; 1935-1936., (744)
  - Sabin, Frances Ellis; 1870- 1 letter; 1935., (745)
  - Sachs, Paul Joseph, 1878-1965. 8 letters; 1934-1948. No.7 signed by secretary., (746)
  - Sage, Evan Taylor, 1881- 1 letter; 1921., (747)
  - Sainte-Marie, Henri de. 1 letter; 1937., (748)
  - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892- 3 letters; 1948-1952., (749)
  - Salvemini, Gaetano, 1873-1957. 4 letters; 1934-1940., (750)
  - Sander, Wilhelm, 1881- 1 letter; 1921., (751)
  - Sanders, Henry Arthur, 1868- 6 letters; 1921-[1943], (751a)
  - Sanford, Eva Matthews. 1 letter; 1928., (752)
  - Sargent, John Garibaldi, 1860-1939. 1 letter; 1928., (753)
  - Sarton, George, 1884-1956. 39 letters; 1935-1954 and [n.d.] No.26 - see also George Sarton to Vilhjalmur Stefansson, no.(1160)., (754)
  - Satterlee, Hugh. 2 letters; 1958. No.1 lacks ending., (755)
  - Savage, John Joseph, 1883- 1 letter; 1950., (756)
  - Scaife, Roger Livingston, 1875- 2 letters; 1945., (757)
  - Scandrett, Richard B., Jr. 1 letter; [n.d.], (758)
  - Schauroth, Edward Grotian, 1 letter; 1937., (759)
  - Schiff, Mortimer, Leo, 1877-1931. 1 letter; 1929., (760)
  - Schoder, Raymond V., 1916- 1 letter; 1954., (761)
  - Schultes, Richard Evans. 16 letters; 1959-1963 and [n.d.], (762)
  - Scott, Austin Wakeman, 1884- 2 letters; 1949-1951., (763)
  - Scott, Donald. 5 letters; 1938-1961., (764)
  - Scott, John Adams, 1867-1947. 3 letters; 1920-1923., (765)
  - Scramuzza, Vincent Mary, 1886-1956. 1 letter; 1939., (766)
  - Scranton, Robert Lorentz, 1912- 2 letters; 1942., (767)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery, 1872-1960. 6 letters; 1937-1947 and [n.d.], (768)
  - Sedgwick, William Thompson, 1855-1921. 1 letter; 1909., (769)
  - Seigle, Samuel B. 1 letter; 1956., (770)
  - Semple, William Tunstall. 6 letters; 1930-1946., (771)
  - Sewall, Oliver D. 2 letters; 1933., (772)
  - Seymour, E.R. 3 letters; 1927-1929., (773)
  - Shapley, Harlow, 1885- 4 letters; 1934-1939., (774)
  - Shepherd, Massey Hamilton, 1913- 1 letter; 1946. Also signed by Sherman E. Johnson., (775)
  - Sherman, Charles Lawton. 2 letters; 1934-1940., (776)
  - Sherman, Stuart Pratt, 1881-1926. 5 letters; 1910-1923. With notes by Arthur Stanley Pease., (777)
  - Shero, Lucius Rogers. 11 letters; 1940-1954., (778)
  - Sherrill, EdgarB. 1 letter; 1918., (779)